[Log In](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/my-sleep-profile) Sleep Quiz

SLEEP PRODUCTS

*  Mattresses
    
    Mattresses
    
    * Best of
    * Reviews
    * Compare
    
*  Bedding
    
    Bedding
    
    * Pillows & Bedding
    * Mattress Toppers & More
    
*  Sleep Solutions
    
    Sleep Solutions
    
    * Sleep Therapy
    * Sleep Environment

SLEEP HEALTH & WELLNESS

*  Mattresses
    
    Mattresses
    
    * [ ]  Best of
        
        * SLEEPER TYPE
        * MATERIAL
        * OTHER
        
    * [ ]  Reviews
        
        * POPULAR BRANDS
        * FOAM
        * HYBRID
        
    * [ ]  Compare
        
        * MATTRESS MATCH
        * POPULAR BRANDS
        * LEARN

*  Bedding
    
    Bedding
    
    * [ ]  Pillows & Bedding
        
        * PILLOWS
        * SHEETS
        * BEDDING
        
    * [ ]  Mattress Toppers & More
        
        * MATTRESS TOPPERS
        * MATTRESS PADS
        * PROTECTORS

*  Sleep Solutions
    
    Sleep Solutions
    
    * [ ]  Sleep Therapy
        
        * CPAP
        * ANTI-SNORING
        * SERVICES & SUPPLEMENTS
        
    * [ ]  Sleep Environment
        
        * SLEEP TECH
        * BED FRAMES
        * PERSONAL CARE PRODUCTS

*  Sleep Health
    
    Sleep Health
    
    * [ ]  Sleep Disorders
        
        * COMMON DISORDERS
        * BREATHING-RELATED
        * MOVEMENT-RELATED
        * TESTING & TREATMENTS
        *  [ Melatonin Dosage: How Much Should You Take](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/melatonin/melatonin-dosage-how-much-should-you-take)[ 94% of Us Drink Caffeinated Beverages. But What Does it do to Our Sleep?](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-news/94-percent-of-us-drink-caffeinated-beverages)
        
    * [ ]  Improve Your Sleep
        
        * SLEEP HABITS
        * SLEEP AIDS
        * TOOLS & PRODUCTS
        *  [ Melatonin Dosage: How Much Should You Take](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/melatonin/melatonin-dosage-how-much-should-you-take)[ 94% of Us Drink Caffeinated Beverages. But What Does it do to Our Sleep?](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-news/94-percent-of-us-drink-caffeinated-beverages)
        
    * [ ]  Understand Your Sleep
        
        * SCIENCE OF SLEEP
        * IMPACTS
        * STATISTICS
        *  [ Melatonin Dosage: How Much Should You Take](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/melatonin/melatonin-dosage-how-much-should-you-take)[ 94% of Us Drink Caffeinated Beverages. But What Does it do to Our Sleep?](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-news/94-percent-of-us-drink-caffeinated-beverages)

*  About Us
    
    About Us
    
    * [ ]  Who We Are
        
        * OUR MISSION
        * OUR MEDICAL TEAM
        * OUR PROCESS

[Log In](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/my-sleep-profile) Sleep Quiz

Privacy Policy
==============

### Introduction

Sleep Doctor Holdings, LLC respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.

This policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide to us through services accessible via www.SleepFoundation.org or any other website, IP address, social media account, iOS app, Android app, web app or other online product or service offered by Us (collectively, the “Service”) and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information.

This policy applies to information we collect through the Service and in email, text, and other electronic messages between you and the Service.

It does not apply to information collected by us offline or through any other means, including on any other website operated by us or any third party or by any third party that may link to or be accessible from or on the Service.

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, do not use the Service. By accessing or using the Service, you agree to the terms of this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time as described below. Your continued use of the Service after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.

### **1. Information We Collect**

We collect information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer, household, or device (“**personal information**“). Personal information does not include:

Publicly available information from government records;

Deidentified or aggregated consumer information;

Information excluded from the scope of the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”), like:

* Health or medical information covered by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) and the California Confidentiality of Medical Information Act (CMIA) or clinical trial data; and
* Personal information covered by certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA), the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) or California Financial Information Privacy Act (FIPA), and the Driver’s Privacy Protection Act of 1994.

In particular, we may collect the following categories of personal information:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Category** | **Common Examples** |
| A. Identifiers | A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, social security number and other similar identifiers. |
| B. Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)) | A name, signature, social security number, physical characteristics or description, address, email address and/or telephone number. Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories. |
| C. Commercial information | Records of products or services, such as newsletters, purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies. |
| D. Internet or other similar network activity | Browsing history, search history, information on a consumer’s interaction with a website, application, or advertisement. |

**_We Collect This Information_**

* Automatically as you navigate through our website, which information may include usage details, IP addresses, and other information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies described in the Section titled “_Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies_” below;
* When you participate in any interactive features of the Service;
* When you sign up for our e-mails, mobile messages, or social media notifications as described in the section titled “_Information We Collect Through Social Media_” below;
* when you provide us with comments, suggestions, or other input; and
* Directly from you when you otherwise provide it to us.

_**Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies**_

As you navigate through and interact with our website, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns, including:

* Details of your visits to the website, such as traffic data, location data, logs, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use; and
* Information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system, and browser type.

We also may use these technologies to collect information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or other online services (e.g., behavioral tracking).

The information we collect helps us to improve the Service and to deliver a better and more personalized service, including by enabling us to:

* Estimate our audience size and usage patterns;
* Store information about your preferences;
* Speed up your searches; and
* Recognize you when you return to our website.

We may also use the information we collect as described in the sections titled “Our Use of Tracking Technologies” and “Third Party Pixels and Cookies” below.

_**Information You Provide to Us**_

If you contact us on or through the Service, the information we collect may include personal information such as name, e-mail address, telephone number, and any other information you provide to us, including records and copies of your correspondence.

### 2. How We Use Your Information

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information, to:

* Fulfill or meet the reason you provided the information;
* Provide, support, personalize, and develop our website, products, and services;
* Create, maintain, customize, and secure your account with us;
* Send marketing communications and other information regarding products, services and promotions;
* Improve the effectiveness of the Service, website, stores, mobile experience and marketing efforts;
* Conduct research and analysis, including focus groups and surveys;
* Process your requests, purchases, transactions, and payments and prevent transactional fraud;
* Respond to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order, or governmental regulations; and
* For any other purpose with your consent.

### 3. Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction.

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy:

* To our affiliates, in which case we will require our affiliates to honor this privacy policy;
* To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by us about the Service users is among the assets transferred;
* With certain business partners to provide requested services that we do not provide directly;
* To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it; and
* With your consent.

We may also disclose your personal information:

* To comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request;
* To enforce or apply our terms of use agreement; and
* If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers or others.

### 4. Our Use of Tracking Technologies

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include:

* **Cookies (or browser cookies).** A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the Service. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to any website used as part of the Service.
* **Flash Cookies.** Certain features of the Service may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on the Service. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. For information about managing your privacy and security settings for Flash cookies, see “Your Privacy Rights” below.
* **Web Beacons.** Pages of the Service may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit us, for example, to count users who have visited those pages and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).

When you use the Service, we may place one or more cookies in your browser. These are required to enable to hold session information as you navigate from page to page within the Service. In addition, we use cookies through the Service to understand visitor and user preferences, improve their experience, and track and analyze usage, navigational and other statistical information.

Most Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features of our Service.

**Third Party Pixels and Cookies**

When you visit our website, log in, register or open an email, cookies, ad beacons, and similar technologies may be used by our online data partners or vendors to associate these activities with information they or others have about you, including your email address. We (or service providers on our behalf) or our affiliates may then send communications and marketing to these email addresses. You may opt out of receiving this advertising by [clicking here](https://app.retention.com/optout).

### 5. Our Retention of Your Information

We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

### 6. Our Protection of Your Information

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect the security of any personal information we process. However, please also remember that we cannot guarantee that the internet itself is 100% secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, transmission of personal information to and from the Service is at your own risk. You should only access the Service within a secure environment.

### 7. Children

Parents should always supervise their children while online. The Service is not designed nor intended to collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen. So that we may comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, we ask that children under the age of thirteen not provide any personal information through the Service. If a child under the age of thirteen has provided us with personal information, we ask that a parent or guardian contact us at the email address provided below.

### 8. International Transfers of Your Information

If you are located in the European Union, your personal information will be transferred to and processed by our personnel located in the United States under the terms of the EU Commission’s model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries (i.e., the standard contractual clauses), pursuant to Decision 2004/915/EC.

### 9. Do Not Track Features

Most web browsers and some mobile operating systems and mobile applications include a Do­Not­Track (“DNT”) feature or setting you can activate to signal your privacy preference not to have data about your online browsing activities monitored and collected. No uniform technology standard for recognizing and implementing DNT signals has been finalized. As such, we do not currently respond to DNT browser signals or any other mechanism that automatically communicates your choice not to be tracked online. If a standard for online tracking is adopted that we must follow in the future, we will inform you about that practice in a revised version of this privacy policy.

### 10. Updates to this Policy

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. The updated version will be indicated by an updated “Last updated” date below and the updated version will be effective as soon as it is accessible. If we make material changes to this privacy policy, we may notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to review this privacy policy frequently to be informed of how we are protecting your information.

### 11. Contacting Us

If you have questions regarding this privacy policy or wish to obtain additional information, please send an e-mail to our Data Protection Officer at [\[email protected\]](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), send mail to Sleep Doctor Holdings, LLC, 1414 NE 42nd St Suite 400, Seattle, WA 98105.

_Last updated: March 3, 2023_

**Sleep Foundation** and **SleepFoundation.org** are not affiliated with the National Sleep Foundation, an independent nonprofit based in Washington, DC.

The content on this website is for informational purposes only. SleepFoundation.org does not provide medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment options.

Sleep Information

Sleep Foundation

Sleep Profile

Your daily habits and environment can significantly impact the quality of your sleep. Take the Sleep Quiz to help inform your sleep improvement journey.

Take the Quiz [Log In](https://www.sleepfoundation.org/my-sleep-profile)

### Explore Sleep Foundation

 Search

© 2024 [Sleep Doctor Holdings](https://sleepdoctor.com/about/), LLC. All rights reserved.
